Douglas Waugh - Senior C# .NET Developer

Contact Details

Mobile phone number: 07863546306

Email address: douglas.waugh.e3@gmail.com

Postal address: 8 Brighton Avenue, London, E17 7NE

Introduction

I write good quality, maintainable code focusing on delivering the highest value to the business in the shortest possible time.

In order to do this I utilise several tools and techniques. These include involving the business, quality assurance and developers in discussions about requirements before development starts, developing testing strategies, writing my code test-first, refactoring both test and production code as I code, and using an automated continuous integration and automated deployment pipeline.

I believe that continuous improvement is possible, both for the development teams and for myself personally, and I enjoy working in teams that have the same ethos.

Primarily I've coded in C# but I also have experience building websites in JavaScript using the AngularJS framework and I've written some Python.

Work Experience

energyhelpline.com, Southwark, London

Jan 2011 - Present : Analyst Developer to Senior Developer

I have worked on and successfully delivered some of energyhelpline's most important projects over the last few years including our RESTful energy comparison and switching API, relied on by Compare the Market and Go Compare, and a rebuild of our own publicly facing site to use our the API using AngularJS and extensive unit testing with Jasmine, which I ended up leading (currently accessible on refresh.energyhelpline.com).

I have helped to improve the development team in several ways including, but not limited to, starting a truly test driven approach within the team, introducing automated deployments, continuously improving the deployment pipeline, improving our recruitment, constructing study programs for more junior team members, and developing testing strategies.

I have developed more of an understanding and appreciation for application architecture having worked on and extended the applications at energyhelpline that are built using the CQRS with Event Sourcing architectural patterns. With the knowledge I have in this area, as well as my

knowledge of OO and TDD, I feel I've been acting as the de-facto lead developer for the team for the last year, supporting other developers with the design and architectural decisions they have been making.

I got to work with some good developers at energyhelpline.com and there is no doubt that I'm a better programmer for it.

WTG Technologies Ltd, Hammersmith, London

Nov 2007 - Jan 2012 : Junior C# Developer to Tech Lead

I was an evangelist for improving the quality of our coding through the adoption of agile and XP practices, always believing that their clients deserved the best we could give them.

I worked on several projects, ending up being technical lead on a project called POLKA; a web application to aid the police with collaboration. I also worked on DORS, a web application to enable people who had committed driving offenses to register for training schemes, and part of a multi-million pound solution to deliver a content managed help and information site for the 2011 UK Census.

I really started my journey towards becoming a better developer at WTG. The first unit tests I wrote where the first units tests ever written on the projects I worked on. I also introduced continuous integration, automated deployments, and tried, with limited success, to get my team mates pairing. I also managed to get introduce an element of agility to the projects, particularly POLKA, by introducing a prioritised backlog of work items and having a member of the clients team work with us at our office one day a week.

E3Media Ltd, Bristol

Aug 2006 - Nov 2007: Freelance Tester to Junior C# Developer

My first real development job, offered to me after two weeks unpaid work experience. I worked on public facing websites for big multinationals such as Triumph motorcycles, Kia cars, and Orange, using the .NET stack. We didn't really have much of a development process apart from hacking things out, but somebody there did have a book on XP which probably sowed the seeds of my future development.

Sharkbite Surf Shop, Bristol

Feb 2005 - Oct 2005 : Shop Assistant to Web Developer

Managed to negotiate a day a week out of the shop to design and build a small e-commerce site in Classic ASP. Gave me my first taste of production development and enough skills to land some work experience at E3Media.

In My Own Time

I've usually got a technical book on the go (currently 'Object Thinking' by David West) and attend events in London's thriving development community. I am committed to my own personal development and I find there are so many interesting subjects within the field. I continue to improve my object oriented design and test driven development skills and I've also read widely around behaviour driven development. I've been a regular attendee of XProLo meetup, it's predecessor Extreme Tuesday Club and the associated conference XPDay as well as the London Software Craftsmanship meetups, favouring the hands-on sessions these days over talks. Recently I've started attending PaaS meetups, excited by the possibilities such platforms can bring to the development build and release process.

I continue to work on my own pet projects and complete katas.

When I'm not staring at a screen I'm fairly active. I do a bit of skateboarding even though I'm old enough to know better, some very amateur surfing, and a I'm currently the captain of Coolhurst's 7th men's tennis team, currently taking Middlesex East Division 8 Summer League by storm, which is more age appropriate.

Certification

Microsoft Certified Developer MCTS ASP.NET 3.5.

Security Clearance

SC Security Clearance

Education

University of Bristol (2003 - 2004) MSc Computer Science

Liverpool John Moores (1997 - 2000) BA (hons.) Business Administration

The Woodroffe School, Lyme Regis (1992 - 1997) A-Levels and GCSEs